Contact

251-395-3740 (Home) ubutler6@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/uriel-butler-07960018b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Project Plans
Omnicell
Interpersonal Skills

Certifications

Hazardous Drug Management Certificate Program

Point-of-Care Testing Certificate Program

Uriel Butler

Implementation Specialist, SSGB, CPht-Adv, CSPT Clarkston, Georgia, United States

Summary

Specialty pharmacy implementation with over 10 years of Inpatient, retail, PBM, Specialty, and Sterile Compounding pharmacy experience. Self - Starter with extensive knowledge of Medicaid and Medicare procedures. Excellent data entry skills and telephone etiquette. I'm detail-oriented with a strong focus on accuracy and efficiency

Experience

TruBridge

Client Implementation Specialist November 2022 - Present (2 years)

This job assists in all aspects of the Implementation including, but not limited to, planning, training reporting, documentation, communication, and issue resolution.

Additional responsibilities encompass mentorship, team leadership, maintain development and education on updates in the software including, but not limited to promoting interoperability, as well as other tasks requiring leadership skills, collaborative communication between departments, and proactive conflict resolution. Provide expert guidance and consultation on Omnicell solutions to internal teams and hospital staff.

Analyze and optimize clinical workflows in collaboration with clinicians and departments (Nursing, Pharmacy, OR, etc.).

Support procedural changes and conduct thorough integrated application testing.

Also assist with consulting software interface and vendor resolutions as well such as pyxis and omnicell

Northside Hospital Pharmacy Technician II May 2022 - November 2022 (7 months)

Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Maintains an established inventory of drugs and commonly used supplies; reorders and stocks items upon delivery to ensure immediate availability. Maintains competency and follows departmental, USP, DEA, and FDA guidelines when repackaging and compounding pharmaceutical products. Properly operates, troubleshoots, monitors, and cleans departmental automation and equipment.

Ensures Pharmacist product verification and facilitates the timely and appropriate distribution of medications to maintain product Responds timely to hospital needs, answering phone calls, receiving and distributing messages, and triaging requests approriately Understands and implements appropriate time management and prioritization of tasks ensuring timely and safe patient care.

Assists with operational support functions, including minor housekeeping activities, inventory management, and department cleaning/disinfecting/ decontaminating standards to maintain the work area on each nursing unit and medication room where omnicell dispensing machine was housed.

Calibrates IV Pumps and other equipment as needed.

Conducts regular quality assurance inspections focused on TJC requirements, including the examination of product and equipment integrity and expiration for omnicell medication dispensing cabinets and pharmacy dispensing robot Maintains competency and follows departmental, OSHA, USP, and EPA guidelines to safely and accurately handle, prepare, distribute, and dispose of hazardous and non-hazardous products.

able to demonstrate competency in at least 2 primary scheduled areas such as sterile compounding, inventory, operating room, controlled

May complete and sign off on orientation and documentation checklists for new technician

May serve as competency evaluator for direct observation competency assessments.

May perform other duties as assigned or requested

Grady Health System Sterile IV pharmacy technician November 2020 - April 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Atlanta Metropolitan Area

Under the direct supervision of a registered pharmacist, procures, receives, prepares, packages, and distributes, and disposes of medications and pharmaceutical supplies to assist the department in providing quality pharmaceutical care for all patients.

Maintains an established inventory of drugs and commonly used supplies; reorders and stocks items upon delivery to ensure immediate availability.

Maintains competency and follows departmental, USP, DEA, and FDA guidelines when repackaging and compounding pharmaceutical products.

Properly operates, troubleshoots, monitors, and cleans departmental automation and equipment.

Ensures Pharmacist product verification and facilitates the timely and appropriate distribution of medications to maintain product Responds timely to hospital needs, answering phone calls, receiving and distributing messages, and triaging requests appro

Understands and implements appropriate time management and prioritization of tasks ensuring timely and safe patient care.

Assists with operational support functions, including minor housekeeping activities, inventory management, and department cleaning/disinfecting/decontaminating standards to maintain the work area.

Calibrates IV Pumps and other equipment as needed.

Conducts regular quality assurance inspections focused on TJC requirements, including the examination of product and equipment integrity and expiration. Maintains competency and follows departmental, OSHA, USP, and EPA guidelines to safely and accurately handle, prepare, distribute, and dispose of hazardous and non-hazardous products.

able to demonstrate competency in at least 2 primary scheduled areas such as sterile compounding, inventory, operating room, controlled

May complete and sign off on orientation and documentation checklists for new technician

May serve as competency evaluator for direct observation competency assessments.

May perform other duties as assigned or requested

Quotum Technologies
Junior Business Analyst
May 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 3 months)

- Business Development during utility analysis and contract negotiations.
- Supported and Collaborated with Business Development and recruitment to produce compelling project proposals, using qualitative and quantitative capabilities.
- Maintains active relationships with customers to determine business requirements and leads requirements gathering meetings.

- Owns the change request process and may coordinate with other teams as necessary. Develops and owns a list of final enhancements.
- Create and deliver appropriate documentation, training, and communication around feature(s) and process changes
- Performed gap analysis and root cause analysis to assist in project valuation and strategic decision-making.
- Interfaced closely with Development, and Management to help guide consultants going forward efficiently.
- Develop and manage incoming pipeline while assisting with opportunity qualification.
- Develop custom solutions and interfaces on the Salesforce Lightning platform using Apex, triggers, Visual Force, CSS, JavaScript, and Lightning Components.
- Create unit tests for Apex and UI code.
- Prepared client presentations and proposals, including analytics and communication.
- Increased effectiveness of staff and tools by recognizing opportunities for process improvement and creating new systems and structures.
- Collected, coordinated and prepared communications and documentation, including customer contracts and utility applications.

Walgreens

Senior Certified Pharmacy Technician August 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 6 months)

United States

Acts as a resource for colleagues; may direct the work of other staff members.

May assist in training of new team members and may provide input to the employees performance evaluations.

May assist supervisor and manager with workflow management to ensure prescriptions are moving through the stages in a timely manner.

Act as a Subject Matter Expert and assists the Pharmacist in reviewing, processing, preparing, filling, labeling and dispensing of medications and supplies.

Arranges work activities so that the pharmaceutical needs of patients are met.

Cleans equipment and maintains all required temperature logs as per corporate Policy and Procedures.

While completing fulfillment functions, checks medication and administration supply inventory for out-of-date products, removes products from inventory and works with the appropriate resource to record out-of-date products in the Expiring Medication log book.

Assists the inventory team with putting away newly received inventory in the appropriate location in the pharmacy. Assists with full inventory and cycle counts.

Where required, mixes and prepares pharmaceutical preparations including IV solutions, compounds, injectable medications, oral medications, topical medications and administration supplies and cleans compounding rooms, IV clean rooms and IV compounding cabinets as per corporate Policy and Procedures.

Aerotek

Specialty Certified Pharmacy Technician (CPhT) October 2018 - May 2020 (1 year 8 months)

- Point of contact for auditing group, nursing-related requests, clinic-related requests, and implementation of processes around controlled substances
- Managed Krystal reports in a database system for pricing, productivity and financial management of the retail pharmacies.
- Managed and trained 3 technician staff members
- Produced and implemented vital training program material
- Lead team strategy inventory management training strategies meetings
- Created pharmacy policy procedures for standardization for a start-up site
- Assist with the management of regulatory accountabilities at each pharmacy site.
- Manage ordering and inventory levels on all centralized supplies.
 Ensure all scanned pharmacy orders are in the correct delivery facility totes.
- Complete checking & resolution of all open orders before delivery departure.
- Timely tracking and dispatch of STAT order for inpatient facility of long-term care
- Follows daily packaging assignments (selecting appropriate medications for packing; packing medications in blister cards, etc.)
- Handle exceptions to completion or confers with supervisor/pharmacist

HGS

Prior Authorization QA Analyst August 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 1 month) roswell,ga

- Managed multiple projects related to quality measures and organizational best practices
- Formulated and implemented curriculum based on knowledge of CMS guidelines for New Hire Soft-Landing Training
- Performed clinical research to support prior authorization request
- Maintained accurate and complete documentation of required information that meets risk management, regulatory, and accreditation requirements
- Coordinated communication, for internal and external medication therapy management service efforts
- Utilizes various proprietary systems: to build, research, process and enter prior authorizations

Anthem

Prior Authorization Pharmacy Technician II March 2015 - March 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Greater Atlanta Area

- Tracked and triage all coverage determination requests for prior authorizations and Medicare Part B recipients.
- Obtained verbal authorizations and request detailed clinical information from prescribers.
- Responded to client inquiries regarding authorization approvals and PBM online applications.
- Determined potential barriers to compliance and identifies solutions to overcome barriers.
- Maintained and enhanced positive relationships with clients and responds to a wide variety of pharmacy-related questions.
- Tracked timeliness of member appeals, request extensions from Grievance and Appeals Specialist if necessary

Walmart

Pharmacy Technician April 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 9 months) perry,ga

 Assisted with inventory management, including verification of quantities, storage, removal of outdated medications, and restocking pharmaceuticals in short supply to prevent being out of stock.

- A developed efficient method for calculating prescription dosages, increasing the speed of dispensing an average of 350 daily prescriptions by 28%.
- Identified 50+ repeating customers and their prescriptions in order to refill
 and label their medications in advance, speeding up transactions by 80% and
 increasing customer satisfaction and loyalty,
- Operated and balanced cash register with an average daily cash flow of \$16,000.
- Completed billing process including prescription intake, entered billing, filing, and customer pick-up info.
- Reduced fines, recalls, audits, and insurance chargebacks, by ensuring federal, state, and privacy requirements continuously.
- Trained all new pharmacy team members and conducted training updates that transpired.
- Implemented daily, and annual inventory task to ensure completion of daily ordering, monthly returns of unsaleable product
- Mastered the intricacies of various medical insurance billing practices, reducing insurance billing issues by 34%
- Coached staff in customer best services practices, improving customer experience, and increasing customer retention rate by 18%

Education

Lithia Springs Comprehensive High School (2009)